<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 | Andrey Minaev</title>
    <link>/publication_types/3/</link>
      <atom:link href="/publication_types/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>3</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>/publication_types/3/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platform Switching: Steering of Consumers by Exclusive Content</title>
      <link>/work_in_progress/platform-switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/work_in_progress/platform-switching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I model consumers&amp;rsquo; switching between the platforms, finding access to the content provided by the platforms. Using rich and unique panel data from an internet service provider (ISP), I test predictions of the model. The platforms steer consumers switching by providing access to the exclusive content not available on other platforms. The steering has a long-term effect, making consumers stay with the new platform even when they do not get access to this exclusive content anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic self-competition: the evidence of rideshare platforms</title>
      <link>/work_in_progress/dynamic-self-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/work_in_progress/dynamic-self-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I model dynamic self-competition and test model predictions using rich data of all shared rides in Chicago in 2018-2020. Rideshare platforms face self-competition for drivers over neighbor locations and use surge-pricing to steer drivers to work in the given area. Surging the price, in turn, makes consumers choose other platforms. Using high precise data of local weather conditions as exogenous demand shifters, I study the interaction between self- and inter-platform competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platform ranking and firms market power</title>
      <link>/work_in_progress/platform-ranking-and-firms-market-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/work_in_progress/platform-ranking-and-firms-market-power/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
