<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 | Andrey Minaev</title>
    <link>/publication_types/3/</link>
      <atom:link href="/publication_types/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>3</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_huaabe706d7cdaa1c48271cfbfb2de3775_271866_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>/publication_types/3/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cost of privacy. Evidence from the hotel booking market (Job Market Paper)</title>
      <link>/publication/the-cost-of-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/the-cost-of-privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In many markets, consumers search costly among alternative options before making a purchase. The way that choices are presented to consumers impacts their search behavior and hence competition and market performance. The search intermediaries use consumers’ personal preferences data to provide personalized advice to consumers on what products to explore first. The paper studies how the market outcomes change with the information the search intermediary has and whether the usage of such data should be restricted. I constructed the general equilibrium model of optimal consumer choice with the search frictions and optimal firms’ pricing. To estimate the model I utilize a rich dataset provided by Expedia, which includes consumers searching and purchase data as well as information on the hotels which consumers observe after filling a search query. Using estimation results I run simulations to evaluate the change in market outcomes under different data usage allowance policies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firms entrance on ranking platforms</title>
      <link>/work_in_progress/firms-entrance-on-ranking-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/work_in_progress/firms-entrance-on-ranking-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paper shows that the entrance of new firms on ranking platforms with ordered consumer&#39;s search (e.g., Amazon and Google) can lead to an increase in the price charged by firms already presented on the market, despite increased market competition. The mechanism is as follows: an entrance of a new firm increases the chances of all other firms on the market to take low positions in the ranking, which, according to standard results of ordered search literature, leads to an increase in firms&amp;rsquo; prices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
